# Sahil Upadhyay

□ Sahilupadhyay424@gmail.com

 □ T827214747 in www.linkedin.com/in/sahil-upadhyay

# **Profile**

Logical and Organized individual, seeking a starting to expand and explore my programming knowledge gathered over past 4 years from Maharishi Dayanand University. Passionate computer enthusiast with good communication skill and good knowledge of Python & Core Java programming including HTML, CSS, JavaScript & SQL

# **Education**

08/2018 – 07/2022 **Bachelor Of Technology**Gurgaon, Haryana *Maharishi Dayanand University* 

Computer Science Engineering: - 73%

04/2018 Class 12

Haldwani, Uttarakhand Aryaman Vikram Birla Institute of Learning

PCM:-77%

05/2016 Class 10

Haldwani, Uttarakhand Aryaman Vikram Birla Institute of Learning

8.0 CGPA

#### **Skills**

Core Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Python Visual Studio, IntelliJ, Eclipse ID

Tools • • • • • •

GitHub, Git, Netlify

# **Professional Experience**

07/2023 – present **J SPIDERS** Noida, India *Trainee* 

As a trainee gained useful insights on Java Full Stack Development along with it gained problem solving ability. During this period worked on projects and acquired proficiency on range of technical skills and languages including Java, HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, SQL.

04/2023 – 05/2023 Sparks Foundation Web Development

Internship

As a Web Development intern, I had the opportunity build the projects like Basic Banking Application Website, made the homepage of Netflix website and In addition to developing the website, I also deployed it and ensured that it was responsive, user-friendly, and accessible on all devices.

# **Projects**

# Weather Application 🛮

Made a Weather Application using HTML, CSS AND JAVASCRIPT and deployed it on Netlify. The application alongside displaying the weather also changes its background picture according to that city or state.

#### Portfolio 🗷

Made a personal portfolio using HTML, CSS and JavaScript and made it responsive to every devices.

## Digital Clock 🛮

Created a Digital Clock using HTML,CSS & JAVASCRIPT. Have focused more on logical functionalities by providing various option in this clock like Stop, Resume, Lapse, Alarm and have created Date feature also

# **Certificates**

# Crash Course on Python By Google $\ \ \, \boxdot$

Completed crash course on Python from Coursera by google

**Web Development Internship** ☑ Done 1 month internship from The Sparks Foundation

### **Interests**

- Coding
  Travelling
- Reading

• Logophile

# Languages

• English • Hindi